Office of the Vice-President, University Services fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Office of the Vice-President, University Services fonds
1970 - 1978
F-207
1.75 m of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Previous names for Vice-President, University Services include: Office of the Vice-President, University and Community Services (1970 - 1971) Office of the Vice-President, Development (1971 - 1973) Office of the Vice-President, University Services (1973 - 1977)
Office of the Vice-President, University Services
In January 1970 the Board of Governors created SFU's third Vice-President position: Vice-President, University and Community Services. By the time Stanley Roberts started in 1971, the position had been renamed Vice-President, Development. Shortly after, the name was changed again to Vice-President, University Services.
In 1971 the Vice-President had five primary responsibilities that included improving public relations through community services; improving internal non-academic activities (university student services); increasing student enrollment; ensuring adequate funding of university functions; and maximizing personnel and budget efficiency.
In 1972 S.T. (Stephen) Stratton resigned as the Director of the Division of University Services. The position of Director was discontinued and Roberts, as Vice-President, assumed full administrative responsibility for University Services. From 1971 to 1977 he reported directly to the university President. By 1972 University Services had expanded to include Alumni Affairs, the Campus Information Centre, the Centre for Communication and the Arts, Chaplain's Service, Counselling Services, Health Services, Residence and Housing, the International Office, the Reading and Study Centre, the Resources Office, School Liaison, the Student Placement Office, University News Service, and the University Theatre. In 1973 Financial Aid and the Daycare Centre were added to his sphere of responsibility, followed by Athletics and Recreation Services in 1974.
From 1972 to 1973 Ian B. Kelsey served as Assistant to the Vice-President, University Services and was followed by William (Bill) Stewart from 1974 to 1977. When Roberts resigned in 1977, the position of Vice-President, University Services was discontinued. Bill Stewart, his former assistant, became the new Director of Student Services (a position Stewart would hold until 1996). In 1981 the title Vice-President, University Development and Extension was resurrected with the appointment of Jack Blaney, but the focus was on expansion of the university, not provision of student services.
published
Full
Published
The title of the fonds is based on the name of its creator.
The fonds consists of records relating to the development and administration of non-academic services for students, staff and faculty at Simon Fraser University. Activities, topics and events documented include the Vice-President's correspondence with university services departments, Student Society, the university community, and provincial and national organizations; participation on university committees; development of projects, programs, and workshops; and publications. Also included are records of the Assistant to Vice-President, University Services.
The types of documents include meeting agendas, minutes, and supporting papers; correspondence and reports; annual reports; statistical studies; budgets and financial working papers; contracts; and publications including student handbooks, brochures, posters, newsletters, and newspaper clippings.
Records in this fonds were originally processed as part of F-54 Campus Community Services where the records had been divided into series based on the tenure of each Dean/Director. During the arrangement and description of F-107 Student Services, the decision was made to integrate the records of F-54 as the records reflected the history and continuous administration of Student Services offices and programs. In keeping with past practices with university fonds, the records of the Vice-President, University Services were removed from F-54 and redescribed as a separate fonds. A concordance has been created that links old F-54 file numbers with their new F-207 file numbers. A paper copy is available in the collection file for F-207 and electronically via the Archives Information System (AIS) database. Please see an archivist for more information.
While the records consist mainly of those created/received by Stanley Roberts, there has been some integration with the records of Steve Stratton who acted as Director of University Services from 1971 to 1972. Stratton's resignation resulted in the transfer and amagamation of his records into Roberts' filing system. The original order of these records is unknown, making it impossible to separate the records so they have been processed as found. Within each series, the records have been arranged chronologically.
Stewart, William A.; Roberts, Stanley; Kelsey, Ian
The records were transferred to Archives through the regular application of university Records Retention Schedules and Disposal Authorities (RRSDAs).
All accessions have been processed as of December 2005. No further accruals are expected as this is a closed fonds.
Records relating to student services functions, projects, committees and offices are widely dispersed throughout processed records in the archival holdings. For more information, please consult the finding aids for F-11 Facilities Management; F-17 Peak Publications Society; F-28 Office of Vice-President, Finance and Administration; F-74 Simon Fraser Student Society; F-80 Recreational Services and Athletics; F-85 Office of the Registrar; F-107 Student Services; F-128 F. Margaret Hayward (regarding the Reading and Study Centre); F-149 SFU Childcare Society, F-186 Lolita Wilson SFU History Collection; F-193 Office of the President; F-200 Office of the Vice-President, Academic and Provost; and F-201 Office of the Associate Vice-President, Academic.
Some files in the fonds have been reviewed and have been deemed open or restricted in part in accordance with the provisions of British Columbia's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (RSBC 1996 c. 165). All remaining files in the fonds are marked 'pending review' and must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release. As a result of the review process, access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult an archivist for more details.
Archival descriptions are available at the series and sub-series levels. File lists are available for every series and sub-series. Appendix A collects all name access points at the series and sub-series levels and acts as a name index.
- Administrative Records, 1970 - 1977; F-207-1; 13 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to the administration of University Services and includes reports on the history, goals and objectives of university services offices; development of staff positions and job descriptions; a proposal for a satellite university of SFU and the feasibility study for a multi-purpose facility at SFU; speeches given by the Vice-President; budget and funding proposals; and the correspondence and minutes of University Services staff meetings, the University Relations Committee, and the Universities Council of British Columbia. Also included is Stan Roberts' personal correspondence. Records include correspondence and working papers, agendas and minutes, resumes, reports, questionnaires, press releases and financial statements.
  Universities Council of British Columbia
  - Administrative History, vol. 1, 1970 - 1977; F-207-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-1.
  - Administrative History, vol. 2, 1970 - 1977; F-207-1-0-0-2
  - Multi-Purpose Facility Reports, 1971; F-207-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-9.
  - Speeches, 1972; F-207-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-7.
  - Statement of Objectives, 1972 - 1975; F-207-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-2.
  - Finance - Budget, 1973 - 1976; F-207-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-5.
  - Finance - Planning, vol. 1, 1974 - 1975; F-207-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-4.
  - Finance - Planning, vol. 2, 1974 - 1975; F-207-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
  - University Services Meetings, 1974 - 1975; F-207-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-3.
  - Universities Council, 1974 - 1975; F-207-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 207-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-6.
  - Discussion Paper on Education Policy, 1975; F-207-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-10.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1977; F-207-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-1-0-8.
- University Correspondence, 1971 - 1977; F-207-2; 38 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the Vice-President's correspondence with members of the university community including the President, Resources Office, Board of Governors, Alumni Association, University Services Office, Resources Office, Residences, Cooperative Education, the Centre for Communications and the Arts, and the Bursar's Office regarding program administration, budgeting, and student concerns. Also included are reports by Lolita Wilson on students in academic difficulty and statistics on course drops, and a planning report for SFU by Arthur Erickson Architects. Records include correspondence and working papers, agendas and minutes, reports, questionnaires, and financial statements.
  Board of Governors; Office of the President; West Coast Review; Canadian Bureau for International Education; Office of the Bursar; Sculptor's Society of British Columbia; University Advancement; Residence and Housing Office; Cooperative Education; School for the Contemporary Arts
  - Chronological correspondence, 1971; F-207-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-23.
  - Residences, 1971 - 1972; F-207-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-13.
  - General, vol. 1, 1971 - 1977; F-207-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-2.
  - General, vol. 2, 1971 - 1977; F-207-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-3.
  - Arts Centre, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-8.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 1, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-25.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 2, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-26.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 3, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-27.
  - Convocation Survey, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-22.
  - Office, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-1.
  - Resources Office, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 207-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-14.
  - Students, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-16.
  - University, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-18.
  - University Services, 1972; F-207-2-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-19.
  - Board of Governors, 1972 - 1973; F-207-2-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-4.
  - President and Vice-President, 1972 - 1974; F-207-2-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-6.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 1, 1973; F-207-2-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-28.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 2, 1973; F-207-2-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-29.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 3, 1973; F-207-2-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-30.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 4, 1973; F-207-2-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-31.
  - Student Attrition Study, 1973; F-207-2-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
  - Planning Report for SFU by Arthur Erickson Architects, 1973; F-207-2-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 207-3)
  - Alumni Association, 1973 - 1974; F-207-2-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-7.
  - President, 1973 - 1977; F-207-2-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-5.
  - West Coast Review, 1973 - 1977; F-207-2-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-21.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 1, 1974; F-207-2-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-32.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 2, 1974; F-207-2-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-33.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 3, 1974; F-207-2-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-34.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 4, 1974; F-207-2-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-35.
  - Government, 1974 - 1975; F-207-2-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-12.
  - Student Recommendations, 1974 - 1975; F-207-2-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-17.
  - Canadian Bureau of International Education, 1974 - 1977; F-207-2-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-10.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 1, 1975; F-207-2-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-36.
  - Chronological correspondence, vol. 2, 1975; F-207-2-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-38.
  - Report on Course Drops by L. Wilson, 1975; F-207-2-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-3-1-0-71.
  - Students in Academic Difficulty, paper by L. Wilson, 1975; F-207-2-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-3-1-0-68.
  - University Village, 1975; F-207-2-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 207-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-20.
  - Bursar's Office, 1975 - 1976; F-207-2-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-9.
  - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-207-2-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-37.
  - Co-operative Education, 1977; F-207-2-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-11.
  - Sculptors Society of British Columbia, 1977; F-207-2-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-2-0-15.
- Subject Files, 1971 - 1978; F-207-3; 21 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the Vice-President's liaison with various departments and projects on campus. For a list of the departments, see Access Points below. Records also consist of adjudication of student bursaries and fees; programming for the "SFU Today" television show; community liaison activities; surveys on non-registering students and student attrition; the student garden plot project; orientation planning; renovation proposals for the rotunda; and a proposed campus poison control centre. Records include correspondence and working papers, financial statements, reports, surveys and publications.
  Records in this sub-series have been left as "subject files" as per the creator's filing system.
  C.K.S.F. Radio; University Advancement; Health, Counselling and Career Centre; Reading and Study Centre; University Communications and Marketing; Placement Office; Campus Information Centre; Office of the Bursar; Simon Fraser Student Society; Residence and Housing Office; Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences; Faculty of Science; Naheeno Park; Office of the Vice-President, Administration; School for the Contemporary Arts; International Activities Office; Office of the Vice-President, Academic and Provost; Simon Fraser University Women's Centre
  Related records can be found in F-207-4, University Services Departments.
  - Radio, 1971 - 1975; F-207-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Restricted in Part
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-25.
  - Resources Offices, 1971 - 1976; F-207-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-15.
  - Health Services, 1972; F-207-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-5.
  - Reading and Study: Activities, 1972; F-207-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-14.
  - University Counselling Service Report, 1972; F-207-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-17.
  - University News Service, 1972; F-207-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-18.
  - University Student Placement Office, 1972; F-207-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-19.
  - Campus Information Centre, 1972 - 1973; F-207-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-2.
  - Bursary Applicants' Financial Status, 1972 - 1973; F-207-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-4.
  - S.F.U. Today T.V. Show, 1972 - 1973; F-207-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Open
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-28.
  - Leave for Political Activity, 1972 - 1974; F-207-3-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-23.
  - Student Society, 1972 - 1974; F-207-3-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-29.
  - Residences, 1972 - 1974; F-207-3-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-42.
  - Fees, 1972 - 1974; F-207-3-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-21.
  - Housing and Residences, 1972 - 1977; F-207-3-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-6.
  - Images Theatre, 1972 - 1977; F-207-3-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 207-5)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-7.
  - Liaison: Community, 1972 - 1978; F-207-3-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-9.
  - Attrition Study, 1973; F-207-3-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-36.
  - Faculty of Arts, 1973; F-207-3-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-20.
  - Faculty of Science, 1973; F-207-3-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-27.
  - Naheeno Park, 1973; F-207-3-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-24.
  - Non-Registering Students Survey, 1973; F-207-3-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-16.
  - Vice-President, Administration Athletics and Recreation, 1973; F-207-3-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-32.
  - Vice-President, Administration Personnel, 1973; F-207-3-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-34.
  - Centre for Communications and the Arts, 1973 - 1974; F-207-3-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-1.
  - International Office, 1973 - 1974; F-207-3-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-8.
  - Orientation, 1973 - 1974; F-207-3-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-11.
  - Proposed Poison Control Centre, 1973 - 1974; F-207-3-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-12.
  - Purcell String Quartet, 1973 - 1977; F-207-3-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-13.
  - Garden Plot Project, 1974; F-207-3-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-22.
  - Vice-President, Administration Audio Visual Centre, 1974; F-207-3-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-33.
  - Rotunda Renovations, 1974 - 1975; F-207-3-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-26.
  - Vice-President, Academic, 1975; F-207-3-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-30.
  - Vice-President, Administration, 1975; F-207-3-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-31.
  - Women's Centre, 1975; F-207-3-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-35.
  - Day Care Centre, 1976; F-207-3-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 207-6)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-54-1-3-0-3.